# Alex J. Broderick

Current Address 6000 Reynolds Drive # 0582, Rochester NY 14623

# Objective

Obtain a challenging entry-level position that will utilize my education and previous work experience to allow for both company and personal growth. Qualifications including economics degree with a business administration minor, currently pursuing a master in business administration, with sturdy skills in communication, leadership, and analytical thinking.

# **Experience**

### Admission Assistant, RIT Undergraduate Admissions

### February 2013-Present

Phone: (518) 788-8014

E-Mail: axb9306@gmail.com

Providing support for Counselors and Staff with handling of applications, channeling of files through acceptance process and creation of decision packets for accepted students. Management of on- and off-campus recruitment events, tasks including registration and day-of event processes.

### Student Ambassador, RIT Undergraduate Admissions

# July 2010-February 2013

Facilitated campus tours to potential students and families by guiding groups around campus and giving information related to the institute. Assisted at office working on various tasks ranging including mailroom handling documents from incoming and outgoing mail, scanning of important documents into office files, and the input of potential students information into RIT's mainframe.

## Orientation Assistant, RIT New Student Orientation

#### August 2009-August 2012

Lead Orientation Assistant ('11)- Responsible for a team of eighteen Orientation Assistants including tasks such as training and motivated team for their groups of new students, facilitating sessions during training week, and working various events during the week of New Student Orientation.

Orientation Assistant ('09,'10,'12)- Oversight of group of sixteen to eighteen new students to RIT and informed them of areas and facilities of campus, directed them to important presentations and advocated needs of all new students and families.

### **Education**

#### **Rochester Institute of Technology**, College of Liberal Arts

September 2008-Februrary 2013

BS/Bachelor of Science in Economics Minor: Business Administration Independent Study: 'Advanced Time Series Analysis'

# Rochester Institute of Technology, Saunders College of Business

February 2013- Present

MBA/Master of Business Administration

# **Leadership Experience**

Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity- Undergraduate Advisory Board First Year Enrichment- Peer Mentor

# Computer Skills

Microsoft Office 2010, Minitab, SAS, Adobe Photoshop, PeopleSoft

## **Relevant Coursework**

Economics for Managers Financial Analysis for Managers Statistical Acceptance Control
Accounting for Managers Organizational Behavior & Leadership Statistical Analysis for Managers

Alex Broderick 6000 Reynolds Drive #582 Rochester, NY 14623 518 788-8014 axb9306@gmail.com

March 29th, 2013

Rochester Institute of Technology 1 Lomb Memorial Drive Rochester, NY 14623

# To Whom It May Concern:

I am currently a graduate student at Rochester Institute of Technology pursuing the Master of Business Administration degree and the opportunity to work in an environment related to my field of study as a Graduate Assistant in a Full-Time Position would be essential to my career goals. A chance to work with you provides knowledgeable work experience, which I could take to assist in completing my degree.

If you review my résumé, you will see that my qualifications indicate an individual that is dedicated and committed to pursuing excellence. Please consider the following:

- BS in Economics, now student of RIT's Saunders College of business, including hands on project work, including my independent study in Advanced Time Series Analysis.
- Completion of over 150 credit hours ranging from Economics, Business, and a handful of Art related courses after Graduation from RIT in February of 2013.
- Experience in diverse groups, including RIT's Division III Men's Varsity Swimming & Diving Team, and Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity.
- Excellent leadership skills and professional work experience, as evidenced by being elected to work for Phi Kappa Tau's National Council the same year I joined the Fraternity. As well as working as a Lead Orientation Assistant.

The reputation of the Rochester Institute of Technology education is learn by doing and the many opportunities a student has to prove themselves through the numerous competitive teams at RIT, academic and athletic. I am confident that my desire to learn and ability to excel would benefit your working community.

Should you agree that I am a strong candidate for a Full Time position, I would welcome the opportunity to speak to you in person. I can be reached at (518) 788 8014 or axb9306@gmail.com. I appreciate your consideration and look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely,

Alex J. Broderick